Guide to the Delmer Daves Papers, 1930-1965
Department of Special Collections
Delmer Daves Papers,
1930-1965
Special Collections M0192
Daves, Delmer, 1904-1977.
38.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Delmer Daves, 1969, John Lea McDaniels, 1984, and the Associates of Stanford University Libraries, 1984.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, play and film scripts, treatments of novels, adaptations, drafts, lists, photographs, diagrams and working papers of Mr. Daves' career in the motion picture industry in Hollywood from 1930 to 1965. Mr. Daves was a writer, director and producer. The collection contains correspondence with many of the industry's leading figures. The contents are important in relating the history, methods and trends of the industry as well as a biographical source on Mr. Daves.
A cartoon collection is listod. Extent: 6 legal file drawers.
KEY
1. All hand notations are Delmer Daves' unless otherwise specified.
2. All sheets are quarto size, written on one side only unless otherwise specified.
3. All sheets consist of one typed page unless otherwise specified.
4. Descriptive symbols can be combined ad libitum, i.e. OPpNAD-Occasional Pen and pencil Notes, Additions, Deletions.
A Autograph
ALS Autograph Letter Signed
ANS Autograph Note Signed
BW Black and White
C Carbon
DD Delmer Daves
F Frequent
IOC Inter-office Communication
IOC-S Inter-office Communication, Signed
JB Julian Blaustein
JIB Joseph I. Breen
JLW Jack L. Warner
JSJ Col. Jason S. Joy
JW Jerry Wald
Legal 8 1/2" × 14"
LS Lew Schreiber
M Mimeographed
Misc. Miscellaneous
MM Molly Mandaville
N Notes
ND No Date
O Occassional
P Pen
P pencil
ph photocopy
PNAD Pen Notes, Additions, Deletions
pNAD pencil Notes, Additions, Deletions
PpNAD Pen and pencil Notes, Additions, Deletions
Prelim. Preliminary
RAK Ray A. Klune
Rev. Revised
Rev. Temp. Revised Temporary
RLHL. R. L. Hough
Size X 7 1/4" × 10 1/2"
SP Screenplay
ST Steve Trilling
T Typed
TLS Typed Letter Signed
TNS Typed Note Signed
vso. verso
WB Warner Brothers
8vo. octavo size
20CF 20th Century Fox
[] information not included but determined by reader
Container List
- Shipmates (Anchors Aweigh) MGM-1931, 1930
  - Original story by Delmer Daves and Lou Edelman, with 2nd treatments. Ribbon typescript with scattered holograph changes and corrections, including some on verso of same pages. ca. 40 pages Carbon typescript of another treatment., 10/21/30; 16 pages (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1st temperary complete screenplay, with treatment. 1st draft carbon typescript with scattered pencil changes, directions, and comments., 111/5/30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Inserted are 11 additional legal size pages of ribbon typescript., Total ca. 250 pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Included in above: an interpolation of Maskee by Ernest Paynter (8/23/30) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 2nd treatment by Paynter in collaboration with Richard Schayer (9/11/30). (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 3rd temporary complete script, original story by Daves and Edelman. Adaptation by R. Sohrock and M.S. Boylan., 12/6/30; Mimeo-130 pages (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 4th temporary script with interpolation by Paynter. Mimeo-with holograph and typescript changes and additions. Signed by Daves on page 117., 12/17/30; ca. 135 pages (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Navy Department, Bureau of Navigation dispatch to Captain William S. Miller., 1/3/31 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - U.S. Naval message concerning Captain William S. Miller., 1/4/31
- Clear All Wires, 1932
  - Final script, adaptation by Bella and Samuel Spewack; screenplay by Delmer Daves. Mimeo-with scattered pencil changes. 182 pages Front cover: (Delmer L. Daves), hand-lettered by Delmer Daves. Back cover: short lists-price, expense, reminders, etc. Sketch of cabin labeled Sanctuary', hand-lettered four times. Name `Geo. Hill' hand-lettered above cabin. Sketch of women in hat with single flower protruding. All drawn and written by Delmer Daves., 12/13/32 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Divorce in the Family, 1932
  - First draft Divorce in the Family, (Father and Sons working title). Dialogue continuity by Delmer Daves. Front page: signed by Delmer Daves, 5/6/32; Mimeo- 112 pages (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 2nd Draft Divorce in the Family, screenplay by Delmer Daves., 6/11/32; Mimeo- 119 pages (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Screenplay treatment of My Kid Brother by Delmer Daves. On verso page 70- holograph notations and suggestions by Delmer Daves., 11/25/31; Mimeo- 70 pages (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 2nd treatment My Kid Brother. Continuity and dialogue treatment by Delmer Daves., 12/14/31; Mimeo- 70 pages (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Shooting script: titled Father and Son. Original story by Maurice Rapf, screenplay by Delmer Daves. On verso page 126, holograph addition to script by Delmer Daves., 6/22/32; Mimeo- 126 pages (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Photograph- unknown man in desert gear, asleep in the shade of a cliff., N.D. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- No More Women (Paramount 1934), 1933
  - Dialogue continuity treatment by Delmer Daves and Grant Leenhouts. Carbon typescript on legal paper., N.D.; ca. 55 pages (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - First draft screenplay by Delmer Daves and Grant Leenhouts. Additional dialogue by Lou Breslow. Directed by Albert Rogell. Carbon typescript on legal paper., 11/2/33; ca. 114 pages (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Original story and treatment by Delmer Daves and Grant Leenhouts. Carbon typescript. Carbon typescript., 10/17/33; 29 pages (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Second story. Ribbon typescript with scattered pencil holograph changes, and typed commentary and suggestions on page 4., N.D.; 10 pages (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Original story and treatment by Delmer Daves and Grant Leenhouts. Ribbon typescript with scattered pencil and ink holograph changed., 10/33; ca. 56 pages (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - First rough draft by Delmer Daves and Grant Leenhouts. Carbon typescript on legal paper., N.D.; ca. 30 pages (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - First script by Delmer Daves and Grant Leenhouts. Screenplay by Delmer Daves, additional dialogue by Lou Breslow. Front cover: signed and addressed by Delmer Daves. Private and confidential statement by A.M. Botsford, including notation `This script is the personal property of Paramount Productions'., 11/9/33; ca. 145 pages (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Flirtation Walk (Warner Brothers 1934), 1934
  - First draft screenplay by Delmer Daves. Pages 1-49 mimeo with frequent holograph changes. Pages 50-114 carbon typescript with frequent holograph changes, probably by Lord with some unidentified writing. Front cover: `Lord's copy' holograph on top of page., N.D.; 114 pages (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Temporary screenplay by Delmer Daves. Mimeo- 120 pages Front cover: signed by Delmer Daves., 2/14/34 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 3rd temporary screenplay by Delmer Daves, supervisor: Robert Lord. Mimeo- 120 pages Front cover: handlettered `Mr. Daves'., 5/3/34 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 2nd final screenplay. Story by Delmer Daves and Lou Edelman. Screenplay by Delmer Daves. Mimeo- ca. 125 pages with scattered pencil holograph changes probably by Lord. Front cover: `Mr. Lord' handlettered top of page., 6/22/34 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Script treatments., N.D.
  - a.) carbon typescript, 36 pages (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - b.) carbon typescript, 23 pages (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Red Cagle Story (West Point) First rough draft by Delmer Daves of early treatment. Front cover: `Cagle story, only copy' hand-lettered and underlined on top of page. Ribbon typescript, N.D.; 34 pages (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Development steps of Flirtation Walk, N.D. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Synopsis of story entitled Forward March by Lou Edelman and Delmer Daves. Carbon typescript on legal paper., 1/30; 3 pages
  - b.) Synposis of Forward March submitted to M.G.M. in June 1930, revised and retitled Eyes Right. In 1930 again retitled Flirtation Walk, by Lou Edelman and Delmer Daves. Carbon typescript on legal paper with scattered ink underlinings., N.D.; 5 pages
  - c.) Synopsis of Eyes Right by Lou Edelman and Delmer Daves. In 1933 revised and retitled Flirtation Walk. Carbon typescript on legal paper with scattered ink underlinings and margin notes., N.D.; 6 pages
  - d.) Synopsis of Flirtation Walk by Lou Edelman and Delmer Daves. Note made: Sold to Warner Brothers Pictures, Inc. in 1933 for $2,500. Carbon typescript on legal paper., N.D.; 6 pages
  - e.) Synopsis of 2nd revised final motion picture scenario of Flirtation Walk. Carbon typescript on legal paper., N.D.; 10 pages
  - Notes on West Point Story. Two copies, ribbon and carbon typescript. Carbon copy has pencil holograph notation, Copies, other taken to trial., N.D.; 5 pages (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Flying Cadet first rough treatment by Delmer Daves. Pencil holograph notation on page 1, partiallly torn off but probably said, Copies, others taken to trial. Carbon typescript., 2/17/32; 22 pages (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Typed excerpts from Delmer Daves' journal, transcribed and signed by Muriel Edgarton., 12/9/33&12/21/33; 2 paged. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Statement of Delmer Daves court interrogatory in case involving Flirtation Walk. Ribbon typescript., N.D.; 25 pages (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Typed letter (carbon): From Delmer Daves to Paul Bern (MGM-Culver City Calif.) 5 pages, 3 copies Envelope addressed to Lou (Edelman) by Delmer Daves and making note of contents of letter-10 report to Paul Bern, 2) Edelman's cable to Delmer Daves, 3) Research film lists on Shipmates., 1/22/31 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Radiogram, Lou Edelman to Delmer Daves, Sent to 5/5 Lurline confirming purchase of Flirtation Walk by Warner Brothers., 12/11/33
  - U.S. Navy Recruiting Bureau, N.Y. Film continuity, and lists of stock film shots to be used and their placement, for Aochors Aweigh. Part 1: Carbon typescript, legal paper, 2 pages. Part 2: Ribbon typescript, legal paper, with frequent pencil and ink checks, underlinings and commernts., 9/1830; 3 pages
- Dames and Miss Pacific Fleet, 1935 Stfanded and Shipmates Forever (all Warner Brothers), 1934
  - Dames by Robert Lord and Delmer Daves. Rough Draft. Carbon typescript., 2/25/34; 29 pages (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Photographs- U.S. Naval Academy. All 8×10 inches. a.) Main dining hall-two views. b.) Lowering life boat by cadets. c.) Entrance exam. d.) Swimming pool. e.) Smoke Park and Bancroft Hall f.) USNA Band. g.) Graduating class in Armory. h.) Memorial Hall., N.D. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Anchors Aweigh, Naval Academy s story. Outline by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript., 4/6/35; 9 pages (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Sheet of strength requirements for entrance into USNA., N.D.; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Western Union telegram from Hal Wallis to Delmer Daves., 4/23/35
  - Western Union telegram from Lou Edelman to Delmer Daves., 4/23/35
  - Western Union telegram from Hal Wallis to Delmer Daves., 4/29/35
  - Postal Telegram from Thomas and Friedman, attorneys for Warner Brothers, NYC. to Delmer Daves., 4/22/35
  - Anchors Aweigh original story by Delmer Daves written at the U.S. Naval Academy, Annapolis, Maryland. Ribbon typescript with scattered pencil and ink holograph changes., 4/35; 50 pages (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Anchors Aweigh by Delmer Daves. Carbon typescript. 63 pages Front cover: `Daves' handlettered in pencil., 5/3/35 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Shipmates Forever (Anchors Aweigh). Sole copy of original screenplay by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript with frequent pencil and ink holograph changes., N.D.; 162 pages (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Stranded adaptation by Delmer Daves, preliminary screenplay. Ribbon typescript with occasional pencil changes., 9/15/34 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Stranded final screenplay. Carbon typescript with scattered pencil changes., 10/20/34 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Miss Pacific Fleet suggested s story outline by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript..14 pages On verso page 14 lettered in blue pencil: `HE2474 Hope'., N.D. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Miss Pacific Fleet synopsis adaptagtation by Delmer Daves. Carbon typescript., N.D.; 29 pages (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Miss Pacific Fleet adaptation and screenplay by Delmer Daves. Carbon typescript with frequent ink holograph changes. 136 pages Also included, 2 pages ribbon typescript `nautical phrase for use in screenplay. Front Cover: `Delmer Daves' hand-lettered (ink)., 11/27/34 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Page Miss Glory; Slim; The Petrified Forest; The Go Getter. (All Warner Brothers)., 1935-36
  - It Shall Be Done (The Go Getter) synopsic treatment by Delmer Daves based on Peter B. Kynes' story The Go Getter. Carbon typescript., N.D.; 6 pages (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Background notes on loss of dirigible `Macon'. Ribbon typescript., N.D.; 4 pages
  - Descriptions of U.S. Navy dirigibles `Macon' and `Akron'. Ribbon typescript., N.D.; 3 pages
  - Background notes on los of dirigible `Akron'. Ribbon typescript.., N.D.; 5 pages
  - Background notes on Army and Navy pensions for those who have lost limbs in service. Ribbon typescript., N.D.; 1 page
  - Background note on lumber strike of 5/18/35. Ribbon typescript with holograph notations in margin., N.D.; 1 page.
  - Treatment of It Shall Be Done by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript with holograph notation by Delmer Daves on page 19., N.D.; 24 pages (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - The Go Getter by Peter B. Kyne. Chapter 1. Carbon typescript., N.D.; 42 pages (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - The Go Getter adaptation and screenplay by Delmer Daves. Carbon typescript., 1/7/36; 126 pages (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - The Go Getter temporary copy of script., 1/14/36; Mimeo- ca. 126 pages (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - The Petrified Forest a play in two acts by Robert E. Sherwood. Copyright 1934., 1934; Mimeo- ca. 126 pages (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Slim treatment by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript with scattered holograph changes by Delmer Daves. Front cover: some multiplication and divison done in pencil., N.D.; 29 pages (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Inter-office communication: from Heny Blanke to Delmer Daves. Sends copy of The Petrified Forest to Daves for his files., 1/2/47 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Slim screenplay by Delmer Daves from the novel by William Wister Haines. Carbon typescript., 11/11/35; 141 p pages. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Slim screenplay by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript with scattered holograph changes by Daves. Front cover: `Delmer Daves' written in pencil and underlined., N.D.; ca. 141 pages (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Page Miss Glory story outline by Delmer Daves and Robert Lord. Front cover: `Daves' hand-letterd in ink on top of page., 1/23/35; Mimeo- 87 pages (Box 5, Folder 3)
- The Sea Hawk (Warner Brothers-1940), 1936
  - Adaptation and screenplay by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript with occasional holograph changes. Front cover: title The Sea Hawk and drawing of sailing ship in ink., N.D.; Mimeo- 196 pages (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Dialogue and continuity treatment by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript with occasional holograph changes. 147 pages Also included: `Language of the 16th Century' ribbon typescript 2 pages., N.D. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Notes and notes on treatment by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript with holograph changes [probably by Daves]., 2/18/36; ca. 43 pages (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 1st synopsic treatment..Ribbon typescript with scattered pencil and ink holograph changes and corrections, including some on verso of same pages. On verso of page 5: Pencil sketch of [Moorish costume]., N.D.; 21 pages (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 2nd revised final script. Screenplay by Seton I. Miller and Howard Koch., 1/30/40; Mimeo- ca. 150 pages (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Collusion (play); La Belle Marseillles (play) It All Came True (novel) (Warner Brothers), 1936-37
  - And It All Came True, copy of n novel by Louis Bromfield. Mimeo-with scattered pencil changes signifying what is to be omitted. Front cover: original title Better than Life crossed out and It All Came True written above in blue crayon., 12/31/35; 230 pages (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - And It All Came True, preliminary treatment and synopsis by Delmer Daves. Carbon typescript. 31 pages Following above: notes, N.D.; 1 page of ribbon typescript. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Notes on Collusion with suggested adaptatation by Delmer Daves., N.D.
    - Notes, ribbon typescript, 11 pages (Box 6, Folder 3)
      (also, Title Page for all 3 parts in Folder 3)
    - Suggested adaptation, carbon typescript, 28 pages. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - General notes on adapting Collusion by Delmer Daves, carbon typescript, 4 pages. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Collusion bby J.E. Harold Terry. Typed copy from author's original manuscripts. Carbon typescript., 12/9/36; ca. 135 pages (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - La Belle Marseilles a play by Pierre Berton; adapted by Madeleine Wcette Ryley., N.D.; Mimeo- ca. 136 pages
- The Singing Marine (Warner Brothers), 1936-37
  - Hong Kong Daily Press 18×22 i inches., 9/20/23; 12 pages (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Marine Corps radio narrative, The Yangtze Patrol no. 5. Mimeo- with holograph changes and deletions. 1st page: `Marine Corps Gazette' penciled above title., N.D.; 8 pages
  - Script for Major Bowes' routine. Ribbon typescript., N.D.; 8 pages
  - Character notes, based on actual Shanghai characters. Ribbon typescript., N.D.; 2 pages
  - Character outlines. Ribbon typescript., N.D.; 4 pages
  - San Diego notes, procedures for a San Diego based Marine. Ribbon typescript., 7/22/24; 3 pages
  - Pencil sketch of a Marine Corps barracks room., N.D.; 1 page
  - Loose pages taken from screenplay. Ribbon typescript., N.D.; 2 pages
  - Partial screenplay (pages 106-173). Ribbon typescript with scattered holograph changed and corrections, including one on verso same page (168)., N.D.; ca. 107 pages (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Typed letter signed: Henry S. Griffin, Pfc. USMC, to Delmer Daves. Concerning Chiness/Marine Corps background information., 7/29/36 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Typed letter signed: H.S. Griffin to Delmer Daves concerning possible nicknames for characters., 8/11/36
  - [UNK] synopsis, The Singing Marine byuDelmer Daves. Ribbon typescript with pencil holograph changes and corrections., N.D.; 22 pages (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Revised treatment by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript with pencil holograph notes on verso page 13., N.D.; 13 pages
  - Short sunopsis, The Singing Marine, by Delmer Daves. Carbon typescript., N.D.; ca. 50 pages (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Short synopsis, The Singing Marine by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript with scattered pencil holograph changes, including some on verso of same pages., 7/23/36; 34 pages (Box 6, Folder 12)
    also: two names on inside of back cover
  - Dialogue continuity treatment by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript with scattered holograph changes and corrections by Daves, including some on verso of same pages., N.D.; 139 pages (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Character outlines by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript. Front cover: signed by Daves., N.D.; 41 pages (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 1st draft of original screenplay by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript with pencil and ink holograph changes including some on verso of same pages., N.D.; 174 pages (Box 7, Folder 2)
- She Married an Artist (Columbia); Professor, Beware!; Moonlight Madness (both Paramount), 1937-38
  - Moonlight and Honeysuckle a play in three acts by George Scarborough. (each act in separate folder), N.D.
    - a.) Act 1: Ribbon typescript with all stage directions underlined in red ink. Front cover: `Only copy' in pencil., 47 pages (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - b.) Act 2: Ribbon typescript with all stage directions underlined in red ink. Front cover: `Only copy' in pencil, top left corner., 52 pages (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - c.) Act 3: Ribbon typescript with all stage directions underlined in red ink. Front cover: `Only copy' in pencil, top left corner., 19 pages (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Moonlight Madness screenplay treatment by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript., N.D.; 61 pages (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Screenplay treatment of Moonlight Madness by Delmer Daves. Carbon typescript. Carbon typescript., 6/16/38; 57 pages (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Synopsis of treatment for Moonlight and Honeysuckle by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript., 6/16/38; 19 pages (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Revised synopsis Moonlight Madness by Delmer Daves. Carbon typescript., 7/7/38; 13 pages (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Typed letter from Delmer Daves to `Andy' concerning revisions in Moonlight Madness. Carbon typescript., 7/9/38; 4 pages
  - Holograph noted by Delmer Daves on Moonlight Madness. On 16 m.o., N.D.; 10 pages
  - I Married an Artist treatment and first draft screenplay by Delmer Daves., N.D.
    - a.) Treatment: Ribbon typescript with holograph changes and corrections, including some on verso same pages., 15 pages (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - b.) 1st draft screenplay: Carbon typescript (pages 1-41), ribbon typescript (pages 41-69)., Total: 69 pages (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - I Married an Artist 1st draft screenplay by Gladys Lehman and Robert Buckner. Carbon typescript. 131 pages Included in above: Note by Delmer Daves concerning his role in writing script. On 16 m.o., 2/15/37 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Also: Mr. Elias in pencil on front cover
  - Professor Beware. synopsis of finish by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript., N.D.; 6 pages (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Professor Beware. 1st draft screenplay by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript., N.D.; 21 pages (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Also: drawing (?) on [UNK] of Paper (3"×5") (Probably unimportant [UNK] has been kept with collection)
  - Professor Beware. outline by Delmer Daves. Ribbon typescript with one holograph addition on page 5. 14 pages Following above: Holograph notes by Daves [UNK] octavo. 1 page, N.D. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Professor Beware. screenplay, revised by Delmer Daves. Carbon typescript with scattered holograph changes and corrections., 10/29/37; ca. 158 pages (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Memorandum from Joseph Breen office-Production code (censors) re: acceptibility of Professor Beware. Carbon typescript., N.D.; 4 pages (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Love Affair (RKO)
  - 1st draft screenplay by Delmer Daves. Legal size paper; complrtrly holograph by Delmer Daves in pencil, including some on verso., N.D.; ca. 123 pages (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Work sheets, on legal paper. Completely holographnin pencil by Delmer Daves. Includes hand notes and scratch work. Some scratch work includes names of actors in Love Affair, title of picture, and name of director hand-lettered in ink by Daves., N.D.; ca. 37 pages (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Revised final script, screenplay by Delmer Daves and Donald O. Stewart. Mimeo- 106 pages Front cover: Ink holograph note by Delmer Daves, exact text as follows: Don had one line left in script after being hired a few weeks to work alone-offer fresh viewpoint-but only viewpoint Leo McCarey could accept had to be w with his own sharing in concept so-we gave Don co-credit in place of Leo's who deserved it-so I gave Mildred Crain my share of original story credit (the basic story happened to me -the girl confessed her life story on the S.S. Chaumplain!), 12/13/38 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Folio containing Love Affair worksheets, dialogue rewrites, notes, and scratch work. Includes:, N.D.
    - a.) 1 page synopsis of story, ribbon typescript. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - b.) Dialogue rewrites-4 different sections, all incomplete. Ribbon typescript with holograph changes and deletions. ca. 24 pages 1st page of one section: signed by Delmer Daves with notation `only copy'.
    - c.) Expanded synopsis of story. Ribbon typescript with scattered holograph changes. ca. 9 pages (incomplete). (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - d.) Worksheets on yellow scratch paper, in pencil and ink holograph by Delmer Daves. Included in above: sketches by Daves of Santa Claus, a plane, flower, chair, horseshoe, and the name `Leo McCarey' ornately hand-lettered., ca. 44 pages (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - e.) Dialogue rewrite holograph notes by Delmer Daves on 16 m.o., 13 pages
      incl, in Folder # 5